( SOFT CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Mr. Faulk ? James Sandin .
Hey , Mr. Sandin .
I talked to John over at repairs , and he took care of it .
It 's all fine .
The system is working without a hitch .
You are going to be locked in tight tonight .
Thank you , sir .
All right , Mr. Faulk . Safe night .
( BEEPS ) ( LINE RINGING )
SUSAN : James Sandin 's office .
Sue ? Yeah , I took care of Faulk .
What do you know , did you hear anything ?
You 're number one , Mr. Sandin .
All right . Yeah . You got it , sir . You came out on top .
Thank you very much . Thank you .
Congratulations to you , too , Susan .
You don 't have to say that .
No , Susan , it 's a team win . Thank you .
Okay . All right , well , safe night .
Safe night , Mr. Sandin .
MALE CALLER ON RADIO : The poor can 't afford to protect themselves .
They 're the victims tonight .
MALE RADIO ANNOUNCER : We all got our own opinions .
That 's what makes this country great .
Holly , line four . What are your Purge plans ?
HOLLY : Locking down behind my brand new security system .
Pete from Northern Virginia , what 's your Purge plan ?
PETE : I 'm gonna hunt down my boss .
That son of a bitch has it coming .
Clearly , more people will be Purging this year than ever before .
American streets will be running red tonight ,
when people release the beast in record numbers .
JAMES : Mr. Cali ! You 're getting one last walk in before lockdown , huh ?
Yep .
Did you do the systems check I recommended ?
Of course . No problems .
Yeah , it 's the same one I use . I only sell the best .
Nobody 's bothering us tonight .
You have a safe night , Mr. Sandin . Thanks .
MALE RADIO ANNOUNCER : Don 't forget to buy your blue Baptisias .
Display those flowers proudly , folks , okay ?
Show your support for this important evening .
Safe night to everyone .
Home again , home again . Jiggity-jig .
FEMALE ANNOUNCER : Release the beast , and Purge in our American streets .
Your New Founding Fathers ... ( TURNS OFF RADIO )
( CAR DOOR CLOSES )
Hey , honey , I 'm home !
MARY : I 'm in the kitchen .
( SIGHS ) What a day , what a day .
Everybody 's doing security checks , it 's crazy .
Traffic 's even worse than last year .
Something smells good .
Hey .
Ta-da ! Ah .
I 'll put them in water , get them outside .
Okay . Where are the kids ?
Their rooms , of course .
( SIGHS ) We got an hour before commencement , right ?
Mmm-hmm . Dinner 's nearly ready ,
so , uh , hurry up . All right .
Well , I have to make a few phone calls . Mmm-hmm .
Oh .
One thing ? Yeah ?
Zoey is getting worse .
She 's been pouting all day . I can 't stand it .
So , you 're gonna have to do something about the Henry situation .
There 's nothing to do about it .
He 's 18 , he 's not getting any younger .
She 's just gonna have to sulk . She 'll get over it .
But I 've got some good news for all of us .
I 'll tell you at dinner .
( WOMAN CHATTERING ON TV )
DR. BUYNAK ON TV : History has proven this over and over again .
We are inherently a violent species .
Wars , genocide , murder .
The denial of our true selves is the problem .
The Purge not only contains societal violence to a single evening ,
but the country-wide catharsis creates psychological stability
by letting us release the aggression we all have inside of us .
I love you .
Let 's growl .
What ?
Growl . Why ?
Because everyone says , " I love you . "
It 's used , and we need to find our own thing .
Oh . Go like this ...
( GROWLS ) ( GIGGLES )
No , I 'll look silly .
Come on . No .
Do it . It 's our way of saying , " I love you . " Try it .
Do it .
( SNARLS )
( JAMES TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
I think my dad 's home .
I 'm sorry , baby . You 've got to get going . ( SIGHS )
I 'm sorry .
And you have to get home before lockdown .
Come on .
Come here .
( BOTH GROWLING )
( GIGGLES )
( MECHANICAL WHIRRING )
Someone 's getting ready for tonight .
Be careful .
GRACE : Mary !
I 'm so glad I caught you .
I come bearing gifts . ( LAUGHS )
What have I done to deserve a gift , Grace ?
Oh , I have a new hobby . Baking . Grace . Mary .
I made way too many cookies .
Hi ! Ooh ! Cookies !
I hope you 're hungry .
Those cookies are crazy good .
( BOTH LAUGHING ) MRS. HALVERSON : They 're lovely .
Have a safe night , ladies .
Bye ! Good night !
Bye ! Thank you , Grace .
Yeah , just what the Halversons needed . More cookies , right ?
Oh !
The new addition you built , it 's just amazing .
Thank you .
Not everyone had the year you did , Mary .
What do you mean ?
You know your husband sold a new security system
to almost every home in this community .
You know , some people are actually saying
this neighborhood paid for that new addition on your home .
Are people really saying that ?
Relax , it 's just good old neighborhood gossip .
Nothing to worry about .
You 're too sensitive .
So , are you having your annual party , Grace ?
No . Too much trouble .
We 're just gonna lock down , watch some Purge events .
Nothing special .
Well , um , thank you for the cookies .
Good night .
You 're welcome .
Have a safe night , Mary .
And you , Grace .
( UTENSILS CLATTERING )
( GASPS )
Christ .
You scared me to death .
( SIGHS )
You can 't keep creeping up on me like that , Charlie .
So , quit playing with Timmy and come help me set the table , kiddo . Okay ?
Now .
( MUTTERING )
( GASPS )
Christ ! Charlie , that 's twice today .
You 're gonna give me a heart attack .
Sorry , Mom .
Look , check it out . I made some adjustments to Timmy .
I installed a night vision program
and I insulated his motor , so you can barely hear him .
And he can now play music to accompany him on his missions .
( TURNS ON ) ( 1920s MUSIC PLAYING )
See ?
He likes songs from olden times . Mmm-hmm .
That is very , very cool .
( TURNS OFF ) ( MUSIC STOPS )
What is it ? What 's bothering you ?
It 's tonight , isn 't it ?
Just remember all the good the Purge does , okay ?
It 's all that matters .
Are you hungry ?
A little bit .
( CHUCKLES ) Good .
Well , take Timmy away and come back and help me finish up , okay ?
Mmm . Okay .
Honey , this food is so good .
Isn 't it amazing ? Not one carb .
Oh , great . Not one .
Well , I 'd like to hear about everybody 's day .
Zoey , you want to go first ?
( BEEPING )
Charlie , what are you doing ?
Sorry , I forgot to take my vitals earlier .
Honey ...
By the way , there 's a slight deviation in my heart rate ,
but other than that ,
nothing to worry about .
JAMES : Okay , thank you .
Zoey , your day .
I don 't want to do this anymore .
It 's stupid .
Okay , fine .
Calc test , piano . Normal day . Mmm-hmm .
Who cares ?
I do . I care , very much .
And what about practice ? You ready for your recital ?
James .
Of course you are , because you 're always ready .
Just make sure your left hand cooperates in that third movement .
( SNAPS FINGERS )
When I 'm listening , that 's what I hear .
All right , can I ...
Does anybody mind ? Can I do my day ?
I have some news . Um ... MARY : Go ahead .
I did it . I did it .
All sales are final ...
And I 'm on top .
My division sold the most upgraded security systems .
Congratulations , Dad . Thank you .
Congratulations , baby .
Thanks . It 's a team effort , you know ?
All right , Charlie , you 're next .
Well , we studied the history of tonight in History .
And in English , I wrote a story
about a man whose love is so powerful , that it can kill people .
So , he cuts out his own heart .
That is so sweet .
You know , he should have cut off his own penis .
Zoey , Zoey ...
Eating dinner , no penises !
( OVERLAPPING PROTESTS ) JAMES : Charlie , don 't encourage her .
Don 't fist-bump that !
( STAMMERS ) We 're not in the dormitorium , okay ?
ZOEY : " Dormitorium ? " Is that even a word ?
Get with the times . God .
( LAUGHING ) ( GLASS CLINKING )
Guys , look what time it is .
Oh , wow , it 's later than I thought .
All right , it 's time for lockdown . Let 's go .
Don 't even think about it .
Hey , give that back . Are we in the zoo ?
Fine , I want this .
Hey , look at this .
Mr. Sabian and Mr. Barbero are going hunting .
That 's daring .
I didn 't know they were going to Purge together .
Are they friends ?
Hmm . The Ferrins are having a party .
Grace said she wasn 't having a party this year .
JAMES : Just thank God we weren 't invited .
She 's nice . But , wow , she 's annoying .
All right , let 's get ready for tonight .
( BEEPING )
As always , just a precaution .
All right , Mr. Cali is starting his lockdown .
Okay .
Are we ready ?
All right , let 's hit it .
( BEEPING )
( WINDOWS SEALING OFF )
( EXHALES SOFTLY )
Okay , Charlie , it 's almost time . Hit it .
MALE ANNOUNCER : Release the beast and Purge in our American streets .
Your New Founding Fathers encourage your participation .
( EMERGENCY SIGNAL BLARING )
( BUZZING )
FEMALE ANNOUNCER : This is not a test .
This is your Emergency Broadcast System
announcing the commencement of the Annual Purge
sanctioned by the U.S. Government .
Weapons of Class Four and lower
have been authorized for use during the Purge .
All other weapons are restricted .
Government officials of ranking 10
have been granted immunity from the Purge
and shall not be harmed .
Commencing at the siren ,
any and all crime , including murder ,
will be legal for 12 continuous hours .
Police , fire and emergency medical services will be unavailable
until tomorrow morning at 7 : 00 AM when the Purge concludes .
Blessed be our New Founding Fathers
and America , a nation reborn .
May God be with you all .
( SIREN BLARING )
( BLARING CONTINUES )
( BOTH SIGHING )
Okay , kids . I know bad things do happen tonight .
But we can afford protection .
So , we 'll be fine , just like always . No worries .
Okay ? Okay ?
Can I go now ?
I would prefer to be miserable in my room .
Of course you may . Thank you for being here .
Where are you going , bud ?
Hey . Charlie .
Why don 't you guys do it ?
Because we don 't feel the need to , Charlie . That 's all .
So , if you felt the need to ,
you would kill someone tonight ?
Look , I know this is difficult to understand at your age ,
but tonight allows people a release
for all the hatred and violence and aggression
that they keep up inside them .
Okay ? And yes ,
if your mother and I were so inclined , uh , we would participate .
Because it works .
You don 't remember how bad it was , Charlie .
The poverty , all the crime .
This night saved our country .
( SIGHS ) Hey ...
Why don 't you go relax ? We 're all done here .
I 've got some paperwork to process to get my bonus .
Then we should watch a movie later with the kids .
( POP MUSIC PLAYING ON EARPHONES )
( THUDDING )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( SIGHS )
Jesus , Henry !
You scared the hell out of me .
Wait , what are you doing here ?
I wanted to surprise you .
So , I snuck in when you were eating .
Baby , you can 't be in here .
My dad will lose his mind if he sees you here now .
Come on .
Aren 't you happy to see me ?
Of course .
FEMALE ANCHOR : We 're looking at some live feeds from around the country
and discussing the Purge with criminologist Tommy Aagaard .
TOMMY : Thanks , Nicole .
Now , is the Purge really about releasing aggression
and containing violence ,
or is it something else ?
Purge detractors often postulate
this evening is actually about the elimination of the poor ,
the needy , the sick .
Those unable to defend themselves .
The eradication of the so-called
" non-contributing members " of society ,
ultimately unburdening the economy .
Is the Purge really about money ?
Either way , crime is down . The economy is flourishing .
( BEEPING )
( GIGGLING )
( PANTS )
I can 't do this .
Um ...
Did I do something ? No . I ... Um ...
I just ...
I didn 't come here to see you .
I came to see your father .
What ? Why ?
It 's time to straighten this out .
He cannot forbid you from seeing me .
That 's crazy .
It might be crazy , but he 's not going to change his mind .
He thinks you 're too old for me .
Talking to him is only going to make him more angry
and he 'll make it more difficult for us .
I promise everything is gonna be okay .
TOMMY ON TV : America was collapsing .
A quadruple dip recession followed by a full market crash .
A skyrocketing debt , multiple wars
and a significant dollar devaluation ...
All precipitating the worst economic disaster
in the history of the United States .
Crime and poverty rose exponentially ,
and the New Founding Fathers , just months after being elected
came up with this audacious notion ,
the decriminalization of murder for one night .
A lawful outlet for American rage .
A way to contain crime .
The undeniable fact is , this is working .
( GUN FIRING )
MARY : I thought I heard gunshots .
A couple of streets back , maybe ?
Gunshots are gonna happen tonight , okay ? It 's nothing .
It 's probably somebody just firing off a few rounds
before going hunting .
Come on . Let 's go relax .
( SIGHS )
Hold on .
Look . He can 't kick me out .
He 's gonna be forced to listen to what I have to say .
I don 't know .
One on one . Man to man , no BS .
I 'm gonna explain to him that sure , I may be older ,
but you 're also very mature .
So age difference is not a problem .
I 'll tell him how much I love you .
JAMES : 10 years ago , we could barely afford rent .
Now we 're thinking about buying a boat . ( LAUGHS )
Crazy .
Yeah ... Uh-oh .
This one has a car garage . ( LAUGHS )
Who needs a car on a boat ?
( PANTING )
BLOODY STRANGER : They 're coming after me .
They 're gonna kill me !
Can anyone hear me ?
Help me ! Someone , please , help me !
They 're coming after me , all right ?
Can anybody help me ?
Please . They killed ...
I just need to get somewhere safe .
Does anybody hear me ?
Look , I won 't hurt you !
I don 't want to die .
I don 't deserve this .
Why won 't anybody help me ?
I just need somewhere to hide .
Somebody , please , just open the door for me . ( GUNS FIRING )
They 're coming , they 're coming . Somebody , please !
They 're gonna kill me !
( BEEPING )
( WINDOWS UNSEALING )
What the hell ?
Come here !
Let 's go ! This way !
Come on !
Hurry !
Come on ! Hurry !
What the hell ?
( BEEPS )
Charlie ! Zoey !
CHARLIE : This way ! Hurry !
Go ! Go !
Hurry !
( GRUNTS )
JAMES : What the hell is going on ?
HENRY : Mr. Sandin .
James , he has a gun ! Henry has a gun !
Oh , my God !
( GROANS ) Henry !
Henry ! Henry !
Oh , God !
James . Are you hit ?
I didn 't hit Zoey , did I ?
I think she 's okay .
Zoey ! Zoey !
MARY : Charlie , come here .
Mom , what 's going on ?
JAMES : Charlie , where is he , huh ?
Where 's the man ?
( STAMMERS ) I don 't know . I don 't understand .
Who is he ? Why did you let him in our home ?
He was hurt . He called for help . No one was helping him .
Charlie , Jesus Christ . What the hell ? Huh ?
We have no idea what this man is capable of .
Enough . Enough , James .
He 's gone . We don 't know what Henry might do .
And we 're not safe out here . We don 't know where Zoey is .
You 're right . Let 's go . Come on .
Come on , come on , come on .
Let 's go . Let 's go .
Henry ! Henry . ( GROANING )
Hang on . ( SOBBING )
Henry !
( GASPING )
Come on .
Henry ? ( CONTINUES SOBBING )
Okay .
Here 's the plan .
You two stay put here , and I 'll just ...
I 'll go out there and I 'm gonna find Zoey
and I 'm gonna bring her back here .
Henry tried to kill you . James ...
I know . Mary , I got to make sure she 's okay .
Okay ? I have to .
He didn 't shoot at me .
I 'll find her ,
I can go . I 'll be fine . No , no , no ...
I can 't let you go with that man out there .
Okay ? I can 't let you do that .
Baby , I ...
Let me go get her .
You just stay here with Charlie . Okay ?
You be careful , okay ?
I will .
Zoey ? Zoey ?
Zoey ? It 's me .
( EXHALES )
You okay , sweetheart ?
Yeah , Mom .
Okay .
ZOEY : Mom ?
Mom ?
Charlie ? Mom ?
Charlie , you wait here . I 'm gonna be right outside the door .
Okay .
Zoey .
Zoey ?
( GUNS FIRING )
Mom ?
Zoey , sweetheart .
Are you okay ? Is Charlie okay ?
Where 's Dad ? Is he all right ? Everyone 's fine .
Morn , I didn 't know Henry was going to do that .
I didn 't know he was going to ... Why would he do that ?
Mom ? Charlie , just give me a second , okay ?
Mom , he died . Keep the door closed .
He 's dead . Henry 's dead . CHARLIE : Mom ?
Mom !
Charlie , just give me a second .
Zoey , let 's see what Charlie wants .
CHARLIE : Mom , now !
What is it , baby ?
You need to see this .
Tell Dad I 'm sorry .
Zoey , please !
Zoey !
JAMES : Zoey ?
Zoey .
( GLASS SHATTERS )
FEMALE FREAK 1 : Hey , Mr. Sandin , are you home ?
( LOCK CLICKS )
Wait , James , I have to talk to you .
Henry is dead .
I killed him .
I know . I saw Zoey .
Is she okay ? Is she hurt ? Is she in there ?
She 's not hurt .
I couldn 't get her to come with me .
( MUFFLED CONVERSATION )
What are we gonna do ?
I have to show you something .
Oh , God , I know .
( DOORBELL RINGS )
That one is saying something .
... and Mrs. Sandin .
Your home tells me you 're good folk , just like us .
One of the " haves . "
And your blue flowers tell me that you support the Purge .
We want to treat you fairly , so listen closely .
Let me introduce us .
We are some fine , young , very educated guys and gals .
We have gotten gussied up in our most terrifying guises ,
as we do every year ,
ready to violate , annihilate , and cleanse our souls .
But things took a turn .
Our target escaped us , and ...
Several of your dear neighbors informed us that you , the Sandins ,
have inexplicably given him sanctuary .
Mr. and Mrs. , the man you 're sheltering is nothing
but a dirty , homeless pig .
A grotesque menace to our just society ,
who had the audacity to fight back ,
killing one of us when we attempted to execute him tonight .
The pig doesn 't know his place ,
and now he needs to be taught a lesson .
You need to return him to us .
Alive .
So that we may Purge as we are entitled .
Here 's the plan , Sandins .
You have until our provisions arrive ,
provisions which will help us break into your elegant home .
If you don 't ...
If you don 't deliver him by the aforementioned time ,
we 'll release the beast on him ...
And on you .
And , um , we can enter any home we want .
And we will want as wanting is our will on this fine night .
Don 't force us to hurt you .
We don 't want to kill our own .
Please , just let us Purge .
Toodle-oo , Sandins .
Cut it . Cut it now .
( ELECTRICITY POWERS DOWN ) ( MARY GASPS )
The monitors are working on backup .
The power 's out in the whole house .
MARY : James , they can 't get in here , right ?
They can 't get into our home .
I don 't know .
It 's hard to say .
You don 't know ?
You sell these security systems .
What do you mean , you don 't know ?
We have tested the system . It works 99 percent of the time .
It looks good . It 's strong . People stay away .
It looks good ?
It 's not built for worst-case scenarios .
Is it impenetrable ? No , nothing 's impenetrable .
Things like this are not supposed to happen in our neighborhood .
Well , they are happening , James .
They 're happening right now . Do you see this ?
Okay , listen , just sit down . Sit down , please .
We gotta calm down . Sit down .
All right . Sit down , sit down . Listen .
Okay , to answer your question , yes , they could get in here .
They could tunnel underneath us .
They could smoke us out .
They could devise a battering ram , okay ?
I 'm sorry , but it 's true . So , here 's what we 're gonna do .
( INHALES DEEPLY )
We 're gonna give them what they want .
We 're gonna find that man and we 're gonna force him outside .
Now , we have guns , and he doesn 't .
But they 'll kill him .
Why should he die ?
It 's him or us , Charlie .
( CLATTERING )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
FEMALE FREAK 1 : Why don 't you give us the homeless man ?
FEMALE FREAK 2 : No one will miss him when he 's gone .
FEMALE FREAK 1 AND 2 : Pretty please . ( GIGGLING )
( INAUDIBLE )
( BEEPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Wait a minute .
Shit .
( JAMES PANTING )
Where is he ?
There he is .
Look at me .
Come on , look over here .
Where are you ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Come on .
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
( THUD ) ( FOOTSTEPS SCURRYING )
( SIGHS )
( BANGING ON DOOR ) POLITE LEADER : Dear Mr. Sandin !
Sorry to interrupt , but I 'd love to have a word .
Meet me by your front door . I just need a moment , good sir .
( BANGING CONTINUES )
There you are .
Thank you for accepting my invitation .
Tell me , why haven 't you delivered the filthy swine to me yet ?
Are you protecting him ?
I surely hope not , Mr. Sandin .
JAMES : No . Of course not .
We just can 't find him .
You see , this is a misunderstanding .
My son let him in .
He 's a young boy . He doesn 't know better .
But I support what occurs here tonight 100 percent , okay ?
( LAUGHING ) I sell security equipment .
So , I would never deny yours ,
or anybody else 's right to Purge .
Just give us the homeless pig , you fuck !
( SIGHS )
Sorry about that .
I don 't condone that kind of behavior .
But just keep in mind , Mr. Sandin ...
He was my friend ,
and you are not .
Our equipment is arriving soon .
And we will get in .
Send out he , or that ...
Will be thee .
I 'll go get him .
You should do that .
Hey , Charlie .
( SNIFFLING )
I don 't know what 's going on .
There are people outside .
Um ...
And Henry 's dead .
I 'll be okay . I have his gun .
Stay where you are .
Please be safe , okay ?
I 'm going to go hide in your secret spot .
No .
All right ? I love you .
Don 't .
Zoey .
Get back .
Into the hall . Let 's go .
Drop your gun .
ZOEY : Dad , please .
Drop it .
JAMES : Don 't hurt her .
BLOODY STRANGER : Lower your weapon .
Zoey , I will not let him hurt you .
Leave her alone , you son of a bitch .
I will let her go when this night is over .
You 're gonna get us all killed . You know that .
They 're coming in here , and they are gonna kill us all .
They are gonna come in here , and they are ... Back up .
You got to leave my family out of this . Okay ?
If you don 't drop your gun ,
I will hurt her and I will hurt you .
We didn 't do anything to you .
We don 't deserve this . I don 't deserve this either .
Now , listen , I don 't want to hurt any of you ,
but I am not dying tonight !
Drop your gun .
Please . Drop it .
Put the gun down .
Listen to me . Okay .
You are going to die tonight .
And you can either die like a man ,
and walk outside there by yourself ,
or you can die like a coward
and get my wife and my children killed along with you .
Okay ? So take that gun away from my daughter 's head !
Shoot him , Mary ! Shoot him ! ( SCREAMS )
Get off me !
( SCREAMS )
BLOODY STRANGER : Stop !
( BLOODY STRANGER GROANS ) Shit . Shit .
Mary ? Mary !
Zoey !
She 's unconscious . She hit her head . ( GROANING )
JAMES : Mary , are you okay ?
We got to get some rope . What ?
Mary , we have to get some rope
and we have to tie him up and get him outside .
And we 're gonna end this goddamn night .
All right ? Do you hear me ?
Okay . Okay .
All right . Come on , Charlie , help me .
Sweetheart ?
Okay , I 'm almost done here . As soon as you get the legs secure ...
You got it ? All right , let me see . Let me see . Good job .
You 're doing great , honey .
Here 's what we 're gonna do . We 're gonna roll him into that chair ,
and we 're gonna drag him outside
and we 're gonna be done , all right ?
Mmm-hmm . You got it ? All right , we ready ?
Charlie , just concentrate on your sister , okay ?
See if she 's waking up .
Except , Charlie , I need the light .
Thank you , son . Okay .
Hey , good job . You 're doing great .
All right . Let me get the chair , here .
Okay , we are almost done .
I 'm gonna pick him up on the count of three , all right ?
You 're gonna help me .
Keep the light on us , Charlie . Ready ? One , two ...
Three ! ( STRAINING )
JAMES : Okay .
Great . Now , let 's get the tape and tape him in there .
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
Whoa ! Hey , hey , hey !
I 've got him , I 've got him . I got him .
Okay . Okay , all right ! ( MUFFLED SCREAMING )
You got to calm down . He 's gonna break this tape !
Press on his wound . What ?
Get the letter opener and press on his wound !
Get the letter opener on the desk !
Grab the letter opener !
No , Mom !
Listen to me . I am just trying to protect my family .
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
Just calm down .
Mom !
JAMES : Come on , do it .
Do it , Mary ! Do it !
Press on his wound !
( MUFFLED SCREAMING ) JAMES : Yes !
Mom !
You want her to do it again ?
Mom , stop !
JAMES : Just do it again , Mary . ( MUFFLED SCREAMING CONTINUES )
Okay . All right .
Okay . Ready to sit in the chair ?
Yeah , he 's ready . Help me up . Help me up .
Ready ? Okay .
( JAMES GRUNTS )
( BOTH PANTING )
Stay there , all right ? Stop it .
Just let me take you in this chair . All right ?
Mary , where 's the tape ?
( TAPE RIPPING )
You are making this much more difficult than it needs to be .
You understand me ? Huh ? ( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Christ , look at us . Look at this man .
Look at what we 're doing to him .
Come on , Mary .
Let 's get this over with .
It 's okay , Mary .
I can 't . Oh , yes , you can .
I need you right now , okay ?
Hey , look at me . Huh ? Look at me , Mary .
Mary .
It 's wrong . It 's so wrong . We don 't have a choice .
This is so wrong .
We don 't have any other choice .
Don 't touch me . Look at you .
No , no , no . Don 't touch me .
When did this happen ?
James , look at you .
What the hell happened to us , James ?
Charlie .
Charlie ? Baby , where did you go ? Charlie ?
Charlie !
Charlie , where are you , baby ?
Zoey . Hey , are you all right ?
Sit down , sit down .
You hit your head . Are you okay ?
Oh , God .
I am so sorry about Henry , okay ?
I 'm so sorry .
But we 're gonna make it through tonight , all right ?
We will , and everything is gonna be okay .
It 's not gonna be okay .
What ?
Look at what you 're doing .
Nothing is ever going to be okay again .
Don 't say that .
Save your children .
Take me outside .
( EXHALES )
Charlie ? Charlie !
( HORNS BLARING )
( ENGINES REVVING )
POLITE LEADER : I want all these barricades down !
Get chains on every door and every window !
James , where 's Zoey ?
I don 't know , she ran out here .
Those freaks outside are coming in !
They have chains on the doors and windows .
They 're gonna pull them off and come inside .
Maybe you were right .
No , I wasn 't right about anything .
You 're not sending him outside ?
I have another idea .
CHARLIE : What are you gonna do ?
BOTH : Charlie !
Charlie , listen to me .
You take this gun .
Dad , are you sending him outside ?
No . All right ?
You 're gonna go hide in the basement
and you 're not gonna come out for anybody , all right ?
Okay . You 're a good boy .
All right , go , go .
You just gave our son a gun .
You want to tell me what the hell we 're doing ?
We 're gonna fight .
I want you to take this one as well . Safety 's off .
You 're gonna use a lot of rounds .
What do I do ?
You 're gonna cover the other side of the house .
This is our home . Our kids live here .
Anybody tries to come in , you blast them .
You will not hesitate . Mmm .
POLITE LEADER : Dear Mr. and Mrs. !
I 'm sorry to tell you this , but your time is essentially up .
And you failed !
You failed to deliver the homeless swine !
I 'm very disappointed as you fine folk should know better !
That piece of filth that you are protecting
exists only to serve our need to Purge !
So , I bid thee farewell , sweet Sandins . ( GUN COCKS )
Release the beast , boys . Let the killing commence !
( ENGINES REVVING )
( TIRES SCREECHING )
POLITE LEADER : Run !
( THUDDING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GUN COCKS )
( DISTANT GUNFIRE ) ( GLASS SHATTERING )
( GRUNTS )
( MACHINE GUN FIRE CONTINUES )
( GLASS SHATTERS )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( THUD )
( FEMALE FREAK LAUGHING )
( GLASS SHATTERING )
( CLATTERING )
( SILENCE )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( GASPS )
( CHARLIE SCREAMING )
Are you okay ? Are you okay ?
Are you hurt ? No , I 'm okay .
We 've got to get out of here .
Come on , come on , come on .
( WHIMPERING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
POLITE LEADER : Cooper , come look at little lady Sandin .
She 's exquisite .
Save her for me .
Dad .
Are you okay ? Yes , Dad , I 'm okay .
You stay here , okay ?
Are Mommy and Zoey okay ?
Yeah , they 're gonna be fine .
( GUN COCKS )
( LAUGHING )
Mmm ...
( BOTH LAUGHING )
Shit .
( BOTH GRUNT )
( GRUNTS )
Shit !
( CHOKING )
( GRUNTS )
( BOTH GRUNT )
( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTING )
( BOTH STRAINING )
( SCREAMS IN PAIN )
( GUN COCKS )
( GROANS SOFTLY )
It 's okay .
( SHUSHING )
Your soul has been cleansed , Mr. Sandin .
You 've Purged .
Just one question for you .
Was his life really worth yours ?
Your family 's ?
Thank you for this unforgettable Purge , Mr. Sandin .
( GASPS )
( YELLS )
No ! No ! No !
( MARY SHRIEKING )
Get off ! Get off of me !
James !
( WHIMPERING )
( GIGGLING )
Let go of me ! Please , don 't !
Please don 't kill me . Please don 't !
James !
Please , don 't ! Please , don 't !
Please !
James !
Please ! Please , don 't !
Don 't ! Please don 't !
( GUNSHOTS )
( JAMES GASPING )
James .
Charlie ! Charlie !
Zoey !
Dad !
Sorry .
Thank you for your sacrifice .
You got a lot of heart , Mr. Sandin .
Blessed be America ...
A nation reborn . ( GUN COCKS )
I 'm so sorry .
( SOBBING )
( BEEPING )
( BEEPING SLOWS )
( BEEPING STOPS )
( ALL SOBBING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Thank you .
We saw that you were having some trouble .
We decided to help you .
You saved us . I don 't know what to say .
( CHUCKLES )
Don 't thank us too much , Mary .
The truth is , you 're ours , not theirs .
What do you mean " ours " ?
What do you mean ? What do you mean " ours " ?
CHARLIE : Dad ?
No , no , no ! Dad !
MARY : Wait ! Wait !
Dad !
James is dead .
Mary and the kids will have to do .
Let 's tie them up . We 'll kill them right here .
No , no , no . What do you mean ?
Wait ! Wait ! Wait !
GRACE : Come on . No ! No !
No !
( SCREAMING ) No ! No ! No !
CHARLIE : Mom ! Mom !
Cali , get the tape !
Don 't touch my fucking children !
Don 't you touch my fucking kids !
( SOBBING )
MARY : Let them go ! Let them go !
Right now ! You let my fucking kids go !
Shut up , Mary ! Shut up !
Right now !
Mary ! Shut up !
( SHUSHES )
I swear to God , I will shoot him right now .
Do you hear me ?
Why are you doing this ? Why are you doing this ?
Why are you doing this right now ?
When your barricades came down ,
we saw an opportunity to cleanse ourselves of our hatred .
You made so much money off of us
and then you just stuck it in our faces .
You all think you 're so damn perfect .
I just need you to listen to me , Grace .
I 'm really begging you right now .
Do not do this to my children , please .
They 're my children , please .
Please , not my children .
I can 't let you do that .
We have to , Mary . That 's what this night is all about .
I am begging you . I 'm really begging you .
I can 't let you do this .
We 'll be better people and you 'll have sacrificed yourselves
to make the world a better place .
CHARLIE : Mom ...
Mom !
You 're frightening them .
Please don 't .
Please let me hold my children .
Mary , no , no . It 's over .
Untie them . It 's over .
Please untie my hands . Hmm ?
Grace ?
It 's time for you to quiet down , Mary ,
and let us do our duty as Americans .
Mom .
Sweetheart ... ( BREATHING SHAKILY )
Zoey , look at me , okay ? Just look at your mama .
Just look at me . Just look at me .
ALL : Blessed be the New Founding Fathers
for letting us Purge and cleanse our souls .
Blessed be America ...
( INAUDIBLE )
Blessed be America , a nation reborn .
I 'll go first and then ...
We 'll take turns .
( 19208 MUSIC PLAYING ON TIMMY )
Timmy ?
Don 't move .
Drop your weapons right now .
Untie them , let 's go .
Right now .
( SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
Your call .
Just get it over with .
Kill us quickly .
No .
Oh , for God 's sake ! Just do it !
Come on !
Mom , they were going to kill us .
It doesn 't matter .
We are gonna play the rest of this night out in motherfucking peace .
Does anyone have a problem with that ?
Did you enjoy Grace 's Purge party ...
Mr. Halverson ?
Go fuck yourself .
Sorry , I can 't hear you .
It was very nice .
Oh , good .
I 'm glad you all had a grand time .
( ZOEY WEEPING )
( GRUNTS )
Didn 't you hear what I said ? No more killing tonight !
Is it that hard to understand ?
( GROANS )
( SIREN BLARING )
Oh , my ... ( GASPS )
Now get the hell out of my house .
( EXHALES )
Wait .
Are you going to be okay ?
Thank you .
Good luck .
( POLICE SIREN WAILING )
( HELICOPTERS HOVERING )
FEMALE ANNOUNCER ON RADIO : Just after 7 : 00 AM , March 22nd ,
the Annual Purge has just concluded .
This is your American morning news program .
And reports are coming in from all around the country
as police , firefighters and paramedics ...
MALE ANNOUNCER 1 : The New Founding Fathers have released an early statement saying
this was the most successful Purge yet .
MALE REPORTER : I am walking ...
I should say " stumbling " through downtown Los Angeles ,
and there are literally bodies everywhere .
MALE CIVILIAN 1 : I witnessed a group of young men
breaking into the tenement next to me ,
and they were dragging people out
and just executing them on the street .
FEMALE ANNOUNCER : Hundreds have gathered in Times Square
for a public vigil
thanking all those who were killed last night
for their sacrifice to make this country a safer place .
MALE CIVILIAN 2 : They are turning people away
from emergency rooms in Brownsville
as there is simply no more room .
MALE ANNOUNCER 2 : The markets were up this morning
as both gun and home security system
quarterly sales reports were released
announcing profits in both sectors .
FEMALE ANNOUNCER : We have 364 long days until the next Purge .
So let 's get all our Purge talk and analysis in today
while our thoughts are still fresh .
From what I 've been reading , it seems like Dallas had the most participants .
I did get a chance to see some live surveillance footage
out of Dallas , Forest Lawn ,
and there had to be 200 people in the town square
Purging at the same time .
Never saw anything like this .
MALE CIVILIAN 3 : I lost my two sons last night .
My boys .
Yeah , I was a proud American .
Not anymore .
This country has taken everything from me .
( RADIO STATIC )
( 19208 MUSIC PLAYING )